Let's build the phone emulator.
In this tutorial, we will cover how to build a USB emulator for mobile devices.
I will introduce you to some of the launch comment options and then we will trigger the build default
areas for an emulator.
Okay, so let's get started.
I'm going to the terminal window.
Okay.
So to start the build we will need to run couple of commence he now in my route speak to follow and
from here you need to run the command to set up the environment.
So this is the command, basically.
So what we are doing here is we are following a script called E and we set up dot assets and this shell
script will help to initialize some of the environment variable for us.
Okay.
And this after initializing the environment, variables will be able to run the airspeed commands.
Just enter.
So now it is initialized.
Now the next step is to see what all lunch options we have.
So there is a lunch menu in aways which will show us what old build flywheels we can build in the areas.
Okay, so if you type lunch, then you will get that list of lunch options.
So here are the lens options.
So at the moment we have 71 build flavors.
But here, just keep in mind that these lunch options are actually four different devices or for different
CPU architecture.
So if you take the first drone, for example, the aerospace engineering oriented, so this is the one
for the architecture.
So you will build it was built for and CPU architecture and this is again for ARM 64 bit architecture.
Okay.
And you can see here they are.
These are specific for the car or the automotive build, the Android automotive build.
Okay.
And you can see these are for CFC of stands for cuttlefish.
So these are specifically for cuttlefish.
And here you can see it is for the phone and TV and here the 64 shows that it's for the 64 bit.
So for now, just keep in mind that the launch options are the build is for different types of devices
or different types of CPU architecture.
So here we'll focus on building the emulator for own devices.
So to build the emulator for iPhone devices, we have to use this command.
So I'm getting here so you can either select the number here or you could simply directly view it like
this.
So lens SDK for x86 64.
So this SDK phone x86 64 is the one, which is the emulator.
And then it gives you an overview of what is going to be built.
You need to wait a couple of seconds.
Speaking more time.
Yeah.
So now this is a summary, but there are different properties like this here.
So it's for now.
Just ignore them.
Just understand that these are actually them.
Environment variables for the build up.
So now let's start the payload with that like you need to type M is for make and give the number of
CPU cores you have.
So in my case, I have 16 logical cores, so I am using m d 16.
So now the build will start.
I think it will take at least 2 hours to complete the entire build depending upon your.
It will vary.
So now the build is successfully completed.
So let's open up the emulator and see whether it runs or not.
So you need a type emulator command.
Okay.
So here you go.
So we have the crispy emulator now and.
Yeah.
So this is the basic once you can go to settings and see the version number and all here come down the
build number is this one.
You already a developer?
Under the version you can see here, Google.
That's it.
So this is how you build the mobile simulator.